# Zhen Wang

CSE, The Ohio State University 274 Dreese Lab, 2015 Neil Ave Columbus, OH 43210

# RESEARCH **INTERESTS**

My research lies in natural language processing, machine learning, and data mining. I'm interested in building up reliable AI powered by data-driven knowledge representation and advanced machine learning algorithms, involving reasoning and interpretability. I discover new knowledge from unstructured data (text), structured data (graph) and model parameters (pre-trained language models). I also build natural language interfaces including dialogue and question answering systems with more transparency and generalizability. I'm recently working on reasoning models over graphs, commonsense representation learning, constrained text generation and prompt-based zero-/few-shot learning.

Email: wang.9215@osu.edu

Website: https://zhenwang9102.github.io

Phone: 614-805-9913

#### **EDUCATION**

### The Ohio State University (OSU)

Columbus, OH, USA PhD candidate, Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering Aug. 2016-Present Advisor: Prof. Huan Sun (Since 2017)

#### Université Nice Sophia Antipolis (UNS)

Nice, France Visiting Student, Polytech Nice Sophia Jan. 2015-July 2015 Individual Study Advisor: Prof. Lionel Fillatre, Prof. Michel Barlaud

# China University of Petroleum (UPC)

Qingdao, China B.S. in Electronic Information Engineering Sep. 2011-July 2015 Graduated as 1st-Ranked Student in Major Overall Ranking

### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### The Ohio State University

Columbus, OH, USA Research Assistant, Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering 2018-Present Advisor: Prof. Huan Sun

#### Microsoft Research Redmond

Redmond, WA, USA Research Intern, Language & Intelligent Assistance Summer 2021 Mentor: Dr. Nebojsa Jojic

# **NEC Labs America**

Princeton, NJ, USA Research Intern, Data Science & System Security Summer 2020 Mentor: Dr. Bo Zong

#### The Ohio State University

Columbus, OH, USA Teaching Assistant, Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering Aug. 2017–Dec. 2017

# ${\bf PUBLICATIONS} \quad \bullet \ \, {\bf Boosting} \ \, {\bf Coherence} \ \, {\bf of} \ \, {\bf Language} \ \, {\bf Models}$

Nikolay Malkin, Zhen Wang, Nebojsa Jojic arXiv.2110.08294 [Paper]

# • Knowledge Transfer between Heterogeneous Sources for Complex Question Answering

Lingbo Mo, Zhen Wang, Jie Zhao, Huan Sun In Submission.

# • Learning Interpretable Word Representations by Commonsense Knowledge Reasoning

Zhen Wang, Bo Zong, Wei Cheng, Xuchao Zhang, Yanchi Liu, Wenchao Yu, Jingchao Ni, Haifeng Chen, Huan Sun In Submission.

• Modeling Context Pair Interaction for Pairwise Tasks on Graphs

Zhen Wang, Bo Zong, Huan Sun

Represedings of WSDM 2021 (Acceptance Pater 18 6% Long) [Paner

Proceedings of WSDM 2021 (Acceptance Rate: 18.6%, Long) [Paper]

Rationalizing Medical Relation Prediction from Corpus-level Statistics
 Zhen Wang, Jennifer Lee, Simon Lin, Huan Sun
 Proceedings of ACL 2020 (Acceptance Rate: 22.7%, Long) [Paper]

- SurfCon: Synonym Discovery on Privacy-Aware Clinical Data

  Zhen Wang, Xiang Yue, Soheil Moosavinasab, Yungui Huang, Simon Lin, Huan Sun

  Proceeding of SIGKDD 2019 (Research Track, Acceptance Rate 14.2%,
  Oral) [Paper, Code]
- Graph Embedding on Biomedical Networks: Methods, Applications, and Evaluations

Xiang Yue, Zhen Wang, Jingong Huang, Srinivasan Parthasarathy, Soheil Moosavinasab, Yungui Huang, Simon M. Lin, Wen Zhang, Ping Zhang, Huan Sun *Bioinformatics*, *Volume 36*, *Issue 4*, *15 February 2020*, *Pages 1241–1251* (Impact factor: **5.610**) [Paper]

- A Comprehensive Study of StaQC for Deep Code Summarization
  Jayavardhan Reddy Peddamail, Ziyu Yao, Zhen Wang, Huan Sun
  Proceedings of SIGKDD 2018 (Deep Learning Day, SPOTLIGHT) [Paper]
- Hessian Regularized Sparse Coding for Human Action Recognition Weifeng Liu, Zhen Wang, Dapeng Tao, Jun Yu

  Proceedings of MMM 2015, Sydney, Australia [Paper]

# HONORS AND AWARDS

• Graduate Student Research Poster Award (Top 5), CSE, OSU	2021
• SIGIR Student Travel Grant	2021
• Rising Star in Data Science, CDAC, University of Chicago	2020
• SIGKDD Student Travel Award	2019
• Excellent Bachelor Degree Thesis Award in Shandong Province, China	2016
• Excellent Graduate Thesis Award of UPC, China	2015
• China Scholarship Council (CSC) Scholarship	2015
- A fully supported half-year visiting program in France	
• National Scholarship, China	2014
• Soong Ching Ling Foundation (SCLF) Scholarship, China	2013
• National Scholarship for Encouragement, China	2012

### SERVICE

- Program Committee: EMNLP 2021, ACL-IJCNLP 2021, NAACL-HLT 2021, NLPCC 2020
- External Reviewer: KDD (2019, 2020), ACL 2018, ICDM 2018

# TEACHING EXPERIENCE

- OSU, Department of Computer Science & Engineering
  - CSE 2111: Modeling and Problem Solving with Spreadsheets and Databases Teaching Assistant, Autumn, 2017
- OSU, Department of Astronomy
  - Panel Discussion: 2001: A Space Odyssey Science Fiction vs Science Fact Panelist, Feb. 2021

# TALKS

- "Surf<br/>Con: Synonym Discovery on Privacy-Aware Clinical Data", KDD 2019, August<br/>  $6^{th},$  Anchorage, Alaska, USA
- "Rationalizing Relation Prediction from Corpus-level Staistics", ACL 2020, July, Online
- "Modeling Context Pair Interaction for Pairwise Tasks on Graphs", WSDM 2021, March, Online